Christopher Bigland — Junior Web Developer

© public CV — please email me for no. 🖄 christopherbigland@gmail.com 🞗 Bristol, UK **in** linkedin.com/in/christopher-bigland **?** github.com/chrisbigland

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an enthusiastic and self-motivated Junior Web Developer, Modern Languages graduate and qualified manager experienced in team working, people and project management, teaching and coaching. Having worked in a fast-paced, high growth e-commerce brand for 4 ½ years, I aim to harness my language learning and communication skills alongside my passion for problem solving to propel me into a new phase of my career within technology as a Junior Web Developer.

SKILLS

- PROGRAMMING HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Node.js.
- PROBLEM SOLVING Developed through extensive years of customer service and leadership experience as well as a web development course during which I broke down projects into smaller tasks and debug issues I encountered.
- COMMUNICATION Evolved through foreign language study, years living in different countries with different languages, English teaching to foreign students and team leadership.
- TEAMWORKING Acquired and advanced working alongside other managers and team leaders at Gymshark, in catering/sales outlets and at university working in groups planning projects and presentations.
- LEADERSHIP/MANAGEMENT Led and developed an exceptionally high-performing and diverse foreign language customer support team at Gymshark. In addition, whilst English teaching I applied a range of techniques to ensure an academically productive learning environment where students were supported and engaged during class.
- ORGANISATION Gained project management skills via my management apprenticeship, successfully implementing a language improvement project for my team at Gymshark. I used a Gantt Chart and covey's matrices to ensure timescales were met and effective tasks prioritised, alongside assessing and mitigating against potential risks. Such planning was essential in this extraordinarily high-growth environment where change occurred frequently.
- FOREIGN LANGUAGES Native English speaker. Advanced C1 level German and Spanish. Basic A2 level Portuguese.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Undertaken as part of my self-paced web development course at _nology, Bristol. Expected finish date — end of December 2022. The code for these can be viewed on my GitHub (see contact section above for link).

CALCULATOR — my first project using JavaScript. I applied my knowledge of functions to create a simple, functioning calculator accepting multiple digits and calculations.

'PAIRS' PORTUGUESE LANGUAGE LEARNING GAME — I chose, designed and developed the game, during which time I progressed my skills in breaking down problems as well as independently debugging and researching new topics to apply. **MORSE CODE TRANSLATOR** — built using JavaScript to translate to and from morse code utilising Object Oriented Programming to translate user input from the DOM. I intend to work on this further to incorporate a new morse code sound feature.

ALIEN INVADERS GAME — advanced JavaScript project utilising an OOP mindset to create a simple, text-only, space invaders inspired game.

'TICKET TRACKER' — a project utilising React to employ newly-gained knowledge of components, rendering, testing and communicating with APIs to create a page displaying a selection of beers that can be filtered according to different criteria.

EMPLOYMENT

Gymshark (UK) Customer Support Foreign Language Team Leader

SEPT 2020 - JUL 2022

I was the first point of contact for mentoring new starters and helping to resolve challenging customer issues within the Foreign Language team, the largest within the department. I regularly conducted quality reviews and 1:1 coaching sessions to enhance the team's quality scores, which improved consistently across the board from the time I assumed the role. I ensured effective training, motivation and support was given, keeping them target-focused and resources optimised whilst fostering a positive team culture where wellbeing and personal development were valued. I started the position before our biggest and most successful ever sale, where we were the highest performing team. The role also involved working with stakeholders across the business, in particular the DACH (German speaking) stakeholders, with whom I developed a strong relationship working together to improve processes and promote campaigns.

Gymshark (UK) German Customer Support Exec./Stand-Up Manager

NOV 2017 - SEPT 2020

I resolved issues for and advised customers across multiple platforms focusing on the Germany/Austria region, translating the official website FAQ pages. I troubleshooted day-to-day German/Spanish translation issues that arose. Identified problems/improvements and liaised with other relevant departments to resolve/implement them. I participated in meetings with the Product team to acquire information and feedback to the rest of the team. I managed a team in a stand-up role for 4 months during the Summer Sale 2019 - monitoring performance, assisting progress and ensuring company policies and procedures were adhered to. I also developed and led a training programme for a wave of new recruits to cover the 2018 Black Friday period, after which I achieved the Employee of the Quarter Award, the first of two occasions I was awarded this.

Previous roles

Roles in English teaching as a foreign language (Spain, Australia), Data Administration(UK) and Customer Services (UK and NZ) detail available upon request.

EDUCATION

_nology — Self-paced Software Developer Course (July 2022 — ongoing. Front-end modules complete. Projected finish date end of Feb 2023)

Chartered Management Institute — Leadership and Management Apprenticeship Level 5 — pass with distinction (Mar 2021 — May 2022)

Nottingham Trent University (UK) - BA German and Spanish - 1st Class (Hons) (2009 – 2013)

REFERENCES

Available upon request.